## Kristen De La Rosa

#### **Full Stack Developer**

Glendale, CA | (609) 865-5130 | Delarosa.kristen@gmail.com | github.com/KristenDLR | linkedin.com/in/kris10-de-la-rosa/ | https://kristendlr.github.io/

#### **Professional Summary**

I am a Web Developer with strong analytical skills and a desire to work with emerging technologies. Purposeful and self-motivated with proficiency in JavaScript, HTML, CSS, and responsive web development with cross-browser compatibility, as well as a track record of learning new technologies. I've experience working collaboratively with talented Product Managers, UX, UI design, and engineers to create software while demonstrating the ability of working on both front end and back-end development. I've a history of producing high quality responsive web applications and exceptional user interface experience with efficient product design.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## 2U Trilogy Education- Full Stack Web Development Program-

Senior Learning Assistant

June 2021 – PRESENT

- Subject matter expert of the full-stack curriculum servicing universities across the United States, Canada, Mexico, Australia, and South Africa
- Mentor students by answering conceptual syntax questions, providing code reviews, aiding with pseudocode, and guiding developers on debug strategies.
- Debug using Jest, Insomnia, and React Developer tools to understand the association of the applications front-end and backend.
- Coordinates junior learning assistance schedules and mentored staff on best practices to debug and communicate coding practices via slack.
- Maintain an average of 92% performance metrics of developer satisfaction in code reviews and debugging in the past 5
  months.

#### Rutgers University Full-stack Bootcamp, NJ— Teaching Assistant

March 2020 - November 2021

- Oversaw code review, and guide activity-based workshops
- Organized teaching materials including class repositories, installation instructions for mySQL, MongoDB, NPM packages, and Insomnia.
- Reinforce key full-stack concepts using Javascript to write applications to be run and deployed on servers, accessing API's, DOM manipulation, test driven-development, and design servers to handle responses and client-side and server-side endpoints.
- Facilitate debugging with students using Chrome Developer Tools.
- Promote a collaborative coding environment in a remote setting using Zoom and Slack.

#### **Livingston Public Schools** — High School History Teacher

2017 - July 2021

- 10 years of teaching experience by creating an environment of continuous learning, collaborative work, and consistent providing academic proficiency reviews.
- Communicated clear learning objectives to students on each unique chapter.
- Attended professional development seminars and workshops to maintain innovative teaching methods.
- Maintained regular verbal and written communication with school counselors and parents to update with student progress, class schedules, and important test dates.
- Provided advice and guidance to students needing morale-boosting and academic advising.
- Pioneered the implementation of different technologies such as technology-based assignments and student response systems to engage students in class instruction and diversify approaches.

## **Featured Projects**

#### Clicker In Space

**Description:** This react application is a memory game of space images. Don't click the same image twice and try to beat your high score! Each image listens for click events. Every time an image is clicked, the images shuffle in a random order.

**Technologies:** This application UI uses React components, manages component state, responds to user events, and is deployed using Heroku.

#### **GifTastic**

**Description:** This application incorporates API data from giphy.com to create a personal GIF archive. It allows user to search GIFs, ratings, and saves the users search history for later use. Access the history through the generated buttons the user is presented with the top 10 search results of their favorite TV shows.

**Technologies:** This application fetches data from Giphy API and uses jQuery functionality to dynamically generate buttons based on user input which is then deployed using Github Pages.

### **Code Quiz**

**Description:** User clicks through an interactive coding quiz then enters initials to save the high score before resetting and starting over.

**Technologies:** This application uses javascript to dynamically generate HTML elements and CSS, stores and retrieve data using the browser's local and session storage, and isdeployed using Github Pages.

#### **Proficient Technology and Skills**

- HTML
- Wireframe
- CSS/SASS
- JavaScript
- React (Redux, Es6)
- Handlesbars.js
- REST API
- AJAX
- Node
- MySQL
- MongoDB
- Express
- Github-version control
- Object-Relational Mapping
- Heroku
- AWS

#### **Soft Skills**

- Verbal and Written Communication
- Flexible
- Leadership
- Collaborative Teamwork
- Patience
- Problem-Solving
- Presentations

#### **EDUCATION**

#### Coding Bootcamp, Full-stack Web Development, 2019 Rutgers University

• Full Stack: Front and Backend Development

# Bachelor of Arts, History and Education, 2010

King's College

- GPA: 3.37
- Honorable Mention
- History Honor Society, Phi Alpha Theta President
- Dean's List

#### **ACTIVITIES**

Volunteer Front End Coder, Hack for LA Project 311-data